Laurel Hu

Barcroft Drive, Fredericton · cell: 506-440-2286 Laurel.hht@gmail.com · Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/laurelhuitinghu/

Over 3+ years of Software Engineer experience in the field of designing, maintenance and testing to cater to the specific needs of clients. I wish to work in a fast-paced environment and a team of motivated individuals who wish to work towards the advancement of the company and its goals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Skills: JAVA, C, C++, C#, Python and Database: PostgreSQL and MsSQL JavaScript.
- Framework: Django, Flask and Spring
- Cloud computing: AWS, IBM Cloud and Azure
- Testing: JUNIT

- CI/CD: Jenkins, Docker and Kubernetes
- Environment: Linux, Mac and Windows.
- Dev tools: Eclipse, IntelliJ and PyCharm

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BACK-END DEVELOPER, IBM SEPTEMBER 2019 – MAY 2021, 2021 – PRESENT

RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Maintained Java application to import data from sources to database, added functions and plugins based on current framework. Use LOG4J for debugging and JUNIT for testing.
- Used **Maven** and **Gradle** scripts for building and deploying the application.
- Developed and managed database using RDBMS concepts including PostgreSQL, MSSQL and experienced in writing SQL queries, PL/SQL, T-SQL, Stored procedures, prepared statements, and triggers.
- Developed and maintained automated CI/CD pipelines on **Git** for deployment using **Jenkins**.
- Built and deployed **Docker** containers to run the application and improve developer workflow, increase scalability, and optimize speed.
- Familiar with the **Agile** environment and experienced in **Scrum Master** role with proven track records of delivering work results.

ACHIEVEMENTS:

- Developed an Incremental import for Java application which reduces the run time for application from approximately 24 hours to 2 hours.
- Designed and implemented a new plug-in in Java which imports data from source through JDBC instead of API calls, the new plug-in eliminates the repeated entries and delays caused by API calls.

BUSINESS CONSULTANT/IT SPECIALIST, IBM, June 2021 – September 2021

- Participated in developing web, mobile applications on cloud (Including AWS, Azure).
- Supported to develop new libraries with **Microservice** architecture using Rest APIs, Spring boot and pivotal cloud foundry.
- Wrote scripts to manage AWS resources from API calls and worked with AWS CLI.

EDUCATION

- BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE, UNIVERSITY OF NEW BRUNSWICK, 2017-2020
- BACHELOR OF FINANCE, UNIVERSITY OF NEW BRUNSWICK, 2011-2015

PERSONAL PROJECTS

CODING TOOL FOR NON-DEVELOPER, BLOCKLY

- Created a visual coding tool built in JavaScript by using Google's Blockly framework, the tool translates draggable and droppable blocks into Python code.
- Tested and documented all the steps for the tool and the tool is also extendable to generate JSON format definition and generator stubs to Python, JavaScript, PHP, Lua and Dart.

GAME DATA WEBSITE

- Built a game data integration website using Python on **Django** framework which collects metadata from game companies through API calls.
- Implemented MVC architecture.
- Designed user interactive web pages using **HTML**, **JavaScript** and implemented CSS for better appearance.
- Deployed the website in **Docker** containers.
- Writing **Python** flask API for retrieving data.

RPG GAME, SPACE ODYSSEY

- Developed a role-playing game with fully-fledged working interactive UI using Unity Canvas
- Wrote code for the action of player and non-player character in programming language C#.